Who goes there?!
誰だ?
グレツ 卜
Gerd, are you worried about your brother?
お兄さんのことが心配なの ?
僕は怖い 怖いんだ
I'm scared. Very scared!
For alchemists to summon a demon...
錬金術師が悪魔を呼ぴ出すなんて…
そんなことが許されるんだろうか?
Can something like that be permitted?
永遠の星の晶 と か 不老不死 と か
Eternal life, never aging, never dying... Do humans really need such things?
そんなものが本当に人間に
必要なことなんだろうか
私には よく分からないけど
I don't really know, but...
でもそれが大いなる万能薬の
秘密に近づく方法なら
But if that is what leads us to discover the great Cure-All Elixir,
それはそれで
仕方のないことなん… あっ…
I think we'll just have to deal with—
僕は永遠の生命が必ずしも
素晴らしいことだとは思わないよ
I don't think eternal life is something beautiful by default.
限りある命でもシルヴイ…
Even if my life is limited, Sylvie, if it's spent together with you...
君と一緒なら
も し仮に永遠の生命を授かつても
Even if I have to give up eternal life, if I can be together with you,
あなたと一緒なら私は怖くない
I won't be scared.
シルヴイ
Sylvie...
認めるのか あんな男を!?
Are you going to acknowledge that guy?!
マイザ一殿は優秀だ
Mr. Maiza has excellent skills.
錬金術師が悪魔召還なと
異端も甚だしい!
Alchemists summoning a demon... That's serious heresy!
Didn't expect that from you, the most inquisitive person of us all.
意外だな
人一倍知りたがりの あんたヵヾ
The great Cure-All Elixir is every alchemist's dream.
大いなる万能薬は
錬金術師の夢です
たとえ悪魔であろうと
それが得られたとしたら
Even if we have to call upon demons, if we can obtain that,
man's history will change.
人類の歴史は変ゎ り ます
デ夕ラメに決まつていようが!
But it's definitely nonsense!
だがも し本当だつたら ?
However, if it turns out to be true,
マイ ザ一は シユネシオスや
ゾシモスにも肩を並ベる
Maiza will come to stand beside Synesius and Zosimus as one of the great alchemists.
偉大な錬金術師かも しれませんよ
みんな笑おう !
Everyone, laugh!
笑顔だ 笑顔 ! ハハハハハハハハハ!
Smile, smile!
There's no need for fear.
何も恐れることはないさ
ヒユ一イ
Huey.
'Tis true without lying, certain and most true.
This is a quote from the Emerald Tablet, which is seen as the foundation of alchemy by European alchemists.
すなるものの奇跡を
成し遂げるにあたっては
That which is below is like that which is above,
下にあるものは
上にあるものに似ており
and that which is above is like that which is below...
上にあるものは
下にあるものに似ている
そして万物は
一なるものの思想によって
To do the miracles of one only thing.
一なるものから得られたように
And as all things have been and arose from one by the meditation of one,
万物は順応によって
この一なるものから生まれた
so all things have their birth from this one thing by adaptation.
そのとおり
Exactly.
すベては 一に通じ 輪は閉じる
Everything is united, and the circle is closed.
我々の者える悪魔が
本当に悪とは限らない
It isn't certain that the demon we're thinking about is evil.
For alchemists to try their hand at black magic, it all comes down to this same thing.
錬金術師が
黒魔術師のは範ち停』こ手を出そうと
すベては 一つに通じている
ヒユ一イは不安じやないの?
Aren't you anxious, Huey?
不安? いいや
Anxious?
No... I'm just very interested in it all.
私はただ興味深いだけだ
How humans will change and live because of the demon and because of the Cure-All Elixir...
悪魔も大いなる万能薬も
それによつて
人カヾどう変わり どう生きるのか…
ただただ興味深い
I can only be interested.
I'm looking forward to it.
楽しみだよ
フツ フフフフ
皆を連れてきてくれませんか
Can you please bring everyone here?
服だけ落ちていた
ビ工一ルの姿がない
Only his clothes were here... We can't find Pierre himself.
The same goes for Italo.
イ夕ロもだ ! イ夕ロもいない!
Italo has disappeared, too.
ん一 どういうことだ
What's going on here?
今から行うことが私にとつて
What I am about to do here...
Whether it is the right thing to do for me, for us, I don't know.
また我々にとって
正しいことなのかどうかは分からない
The one who taught me this is a man who once attended the same school as me.
私にこれを伝えたのは
かつて私と同門だつた男だ
その男は私の祖父の代から
年を取ることはなかった
The man hasn't aged since my grandfather's generation.
今から300年前に悪魔を呼ぴ出 し
He could manage this because he had summoned a demon 300 years ago...
大いなる万能薬を得ることに
成功したからである
and succeeded in obtaining the Cure-All Elixir.
その男は蓼旨 なおどこかで
生存していることだろう
Even now, that man is probably living out there somewhere.
一切 年を取ることなく
Without aging at all...
だ力ヾ大いなる万能薬に近づくことは
我々 錬金術師の悲願である!
However, obtaining the Cure-All Elixir is our, the alchemists', eternal desire.
私はここに魔族の召還を実行する
I am going to perform the summoning of a demon now.
得ることによつて失うものより
Believing there is more worth in the gain from obtaining it than what is lost by obtaining it,
得ることによつて 得るもののほうが
価値あると信じて!
同胞たちよ
どうか最後まで見守つてほしい
my fellow alchemists, please watch over me until the last moment.
害ん暮ろ郎 グレッ 卜
Denkro, Gerd...
なんじ
我 ここに汝を召還す!
汝は天にして地!
I call upon you here!
You are the earth and the heavens! Day and night! Light and dark! Good and evil!
夜にして昼! 闇にして光!
善にして悪!
見る者にして見られし者!
He who watches and he who is watched! He who creates and destroys!
創造をもたらす者にして
破壊をもたらす者!
会を愛し 人を憎悪する者 !
He who loves and hates people. You—
That's more than enough.
C悪簾の声丿 ナ分左
What happened?
何があったんですか蝿
We don't know! It's a monster!
分からなL\! 化け物だ !
何かヵヾいるんだ!
There's something there!
It's a demon! It must be a demon rampaging there!
悪魔だ !
きっとあの悪魔が暴れてるんだ!
あのグレッ卜は グレッ卜は
どうしたか知りませんか!?
What about Gerd? Does anyone know what happened to Gerd?!
Summoning chants are nothing more than complaints.
C雷簾の声丿
呼びヵノプの言葉など
レよ せんな渠り言に すきん
俺は 〔 )フ誓も
お蔚庭ちの言葉す周ごるレ
I can always hear what you are saying.
お蔚庭 ちヵ何す者え ごるヵも
分ヵ フ ごC )る
I also know what you are thinking.
お蔚庭 ちヵ俺のこ ご き者え力ば
もう俺はそこ仁蝿るのさ
If only you think of me, I am already there.
But all right.
There is no need to call my name.
C雷簾の声丿
蒼の名き呼憑ゞ必賣なな〔 )
そもそも悪簾磋呼ば力るのには
約得レご‥な‥…
I haven't agreed that you should call me a demon in the first place,
but all right.
とノごヵることな
分ヵフごる
I know what you are thinking anyway.
You want to know everything about eternal youth, right?
不老不死の すべごヵ淘 り庭のだろ う ?
I shall only teach you.
お蔚だソプノご教え ごやろ う
The method to making the thing you call the Cure-All Elixir.
お廟庭ちの言う
弐〔 )なる万詣薬 'の作 り方き
なぜ私に
Why to me?!
C雷簾の声丿
そ杓 き飲めば不老不死ノごな杓 る
If you drink that, you shall obtain eternal youth.
Now, drink!
さぁ 飲め
宣ベごき知り庭‥のなら
ま ずは飲ゐて とだ
If you want to know everything, you will have to drink first.
縄‥
フ ツ 爺さん
早死ノごレ庭 ようだな
Old man, looks like you want to avoid death badly.
I only want to end this farce quickly.
茶番は早く
終わらせようというまでた
やは り ベテンではないか !
It's all deceit after all!
C雷簾の声丿
こ う 誓輩 レな〔 )と信用誓きな〔 )ヵ ?
You won't believe me unless I do this, you mean?
C雷簾の声丿
どうだ 爺さん 不老不死の感瘻亭煤 ?
How do you feel, old man,
about having obtained eternal youth?
Calm down!
C悪簾の声丿
落ち着ノプ 夕ンカ 實るなよ
悪は気蔚肌 忙 )ん左
Don't fight now.
I am generous.
There is enough of the Cure-All Elixir for everyone in the room.
その 鬼 )なる万詣薬は
ここノごC )る入数分だノプある
Brother...
兄さん
Gerd...
グレッ 卜…
C雷簾の声丿
〔 ) く フヵソ滲 一ル き決め ごおこ うヵ
Let me set a few rules for you.
もレ お蔚奉 ちヵ不死ノご飽き
死ノご庭乙 )ご者え庭ら ?
If you get tired of being immortal and wish to die,
go straight for one of your friends and let them eat you.
迷ゎ ずノ敏晨フの所く 行 っ ご
貪 フ ごも らえ
貪うご言フ ごも口ヵらじやな蝿
And by "eat," I don't mean by mouth.
You do it with your right hand.
石手ヵらだ
自分の亘享ノご右手きの せ ごも ら C )
相手ヵ罠こ 嘘こ ) と,悪 うだけ さ
You place your right hand on top of one's head, and by just thinking, "I want to eat,"
お蔚は石手ノご痰乙 )込 ま力る
you will swallow them into your right hand.
入生峡終ゎ りだ
That person's life will have ended.
ま庭 そカノごよフ ご貪フ奉入層ヲな
And because of that, those who have eaten someone will obtain all the knowledge and experiences of those they have eaten.
貪ゎ力庭入晨フの荊識 経悪き實べて
受ノプ継ぐことノごなる
逆ノご荊識き与え る畦も
石手き相手の亘す仁 の 甘ろ
It works the other way around, too. When you wish to share some of your knowledge,
put your right hand on the other's head. That is all you need to do.
そ力だけ 誓済む
もう7フ
I have one more rule. Amongst those who drank the elixir, it is forbidden to use false names.
こ カ き飲んだ者は
偽名ヵ僅えなくなること仁レよう
不死す同丈 誓峡
本名 さレヵ会話 誓きな
Immortals will only be able to talk with each other using their real names.
Because if you don't, you might never be able to find other Immortals.
そうレなC )と
相手き永遠ノご搜レ麟 すこ とヵ
さきなくなっごレまぅからな
Oops, I almost forgot another really important thing.
ああ おっ と
肝ノ殲ーな こ と き,悪カ ごこ 嘘
If you wish to know how to make this elixir, ask the one who summoned me.
も レ この薬の謂合法き荊 り奉ノプカぱ
俺き呼び髑レ庭 その男ノご薗〔 )
知識を封印するだと蝿
何のつもりだ マイザ一!
You want to seal the knowledge?!
What are you trying to do, Maiza?!
一晩じっくり者えたうえでの
結論です
It's the conclusion I came to after thinking all night.
あれを飲むのは 我々だけに
とどめておいたほうがよい
It is better if it remains among just those of us who drank it.
危険すきます
It is too dangerous.
危険だからこそ
知識が必要なのではないか!
We need the knowledge, precisely because it's dangerous!
セラ一ドさん… 私はあなたほど
人間を信用できないのです
Mr. Szilard, I just can't be as trusting of people as you are.
それは皮肉か
Are you being sarcastic?
いいえ 正直な感慨です
No, it's what I truly think.
ご老体 俺は何となく
マイ ザ一に賛成なんだ
Old man, I kind of agree with Maiza... Though only kind of, at best.
あくまでも何となく…
なんだけどな
どういうことだ)?
What do you mean?
こうして不老不死に
なつてみたわけだけどな…
We have obtained eternal youth through this.
自分がこれといって
変わつたわけじゃない
However, it's not like we have changed.
いつものままだ
We're the same as before.
このまま死なず 年も取らず
生きていっても
Even if we continue to live like this without aging,
そうじゃない人と何も
変わらないんじゃないかって気がする
I feel that nothing's going to change with those who aren't immortal.
一方で とっても
悲しくなるような気もするし
Additionally, on one hand, I feel that things are going to be pretty sad,
but on the other hand, I also feel that things might become quite fun.
とつても楽しくなるような気もする
何にしてもだ
これは本当に何となく
No matter what happens,
though this is just a vague sense of mine...
何となくなんだけどな
俺たちのような人間は
多くないほうがいいと思う
I think it's better if there's only a few of us.
That's no argument!
理屈になつておらんゎ)
分かつてる でもご老体
I know,
but I also feel that what I'm saying isn't all that far from the truth.
俺は自分の言っ乙ることが
そう的外れでもないと
直感 してるんだ
ハツ!
工ルマ一殿を支持する
I support Mr. Elmer.
したヵヾつて
マイ ザ一殿の判断に従おう
And as such, I will follow Maiza's judgment.
何を ?
Why, you—
僕は兄の判断を支持します
I support my brother's judgment as well.
私もマイザ一さんに従います
I will obey Mr. Maiza as well.
知識を分け合うことは
後々でも可能です
We can always share the knowledge in the future.
It won't be too late after we know where we're going.
私たちの行く末を見極めてからでも
遅くはないでしよう
マイザ一の判断に従います
I will follow Maiza's judgment.
フ工丿しメ一卜がそう言うなら僕も…
If Fermet says so, I will do so, too.
マイ ザ一に従う
I will follow Maiza.
I will, too.
俺もマイザ一に
I suspend my vote.
保留だ
ここでみんなで話し合つても
結論カヾ出る問題ではない
Even if we talk here amongst us all,
this is not a problem that presents an easy conclusion.
ましてや多数決で
決めるベきことでもない
And what's more, it's not a problem you can decide with a majority vote.
私の者えは おおかた
工丿しマ一やフ工ルメ一卜と同じだが
I agree mostly with Fermet and Elmer.
However, I just can't announce my opinion while I have just a vague sense of it,
私には…
何となくでは 意見を
表明することができなくてね
だから 保留にさせて頂く
so I'm going to delay my opinion.
結論は いつ出すんだ?
When will you let us know your decision?
Well... It might be in 100 years, it might be in 200.
さ あ    ー 00年後か200年後か
いずれにしても我々にとっては
もはや遅い決断ではないだろう?
Anyway, even then, it won't be too late for us to decide.
ありがとう 同胞たち
Thank you, fellow alchemists.
それでは
大いなる万能薬に関する知識は
Well then, I shall keep any knowledge pertaining to the Cure-All Elixir...
当面 私の内にとどめるということに
させてもらいます
in my home for the time being.
Gerd?
グレツ 卜?
うつ あっ
グレッ卜 私は後悔している
Gerd, I'm regretting my actions.
There is knowledge humans shouldn't possess after all.
やはり人間には
知るベきでない知識もあるのだ
これは危険だ
This is dangerous.
憎しみ合う者同士だけでなく
This will create conflict not just between those who hate each other already,
but also among those who love each other.
愛し合う者同士にも
争いを起こさせる
兄さん それはどういうこと?
Brother,
what do you mean by that?
Actually, I'm really hesitating right now...
現に私は今 迷つている
セラ一ドを食つてしまおうか
どうかとね
as to whether to eat Szilard or not.
私も あの男も
さして変わりはないのだ
He and I are not that different.
Brother...
兄さん‥
だがグレッ卜
However, Gerd, if a wonderful person were to become immortal,
不死者となるの力ヾ
素晴らしい人間
この世に幸福や奇跡を
もたらす人間だとしたら…
and he brought happiness and wonders to the world,
this knowledge would become irreplaceable.
この知識は
かけヵヾえのないものとなるだろう
だからグレッ卜 私は今から半分だけ
この知識をお前に分け与えようと思う
That's why, Gerd, I'm thinking of sharing half of my knowledge with you.
も し お前が
そのような人間に出会ったら
If you should ever meet such a wonderful person, come right to me.
迷ゎず私の元へ来るがよい
も し その時 私が
この世にいなかつたら…
If by any chance I'm no longer in this world by then,
この半分の知識と お前の力で
薬の秘密を探し当てるんだ
use half of this knowledge, along with your power, to search for the secret of this medicine.
やめて… 僕にはそんな責任
大きすきて
Stop it.
The responsibility is too large for me.
Gerd...
グレッ卜! この船で心から
信用できるのは お前だけだ
You're the only one I can really trust on this ship.
You are the only one who is truly pure of heart.
真の純真さを備え乙いるのは
お前だけ…
受け入れてほしい
I want you to accept this.
これは私たちの運命だ
It is our destiny.
兄さん
Brother...
すまない
Thanks.
Brother...
兄さん
やめろ マイザ一
Stop it, Maiza!
工丿 しマ一
Elmer...
ダメだ… こんなのはダメだ
It's not right. It's not right to do this.
いずれセラ一ドは害をなします
Szilard will eventually inflict harm!
そのうち誰かが
食い合いを始めるだろう
At some time, someone will start the eating,
but you can't be the one to start!
だが あんたが始めち やダメだ
工丿 しマ一
Elmer...
笑おう マイザ一
Let's laugh, Maiza!
そんな爺さんでも
変わるかもしれないぜ
Even that old man might change someday.
これは…
What's this?
To think I'd get to devour a little girl in a place like this...
こんな場所で若い娘を
食らうことになろうとは
Was it you?
あなただつたの
性欲など
とうに尽きておるはずが…
I should have lost my sexual desire a long time ago, but...
there's a voice within me that longs for you.
わしの中で
お前を求める声がする…
そうか あの若造
お前に惚れていたようだな
I see...
It seems the young lad was in love with you.
それはどういう意味?
What do you... mean by that?
やめて… やめて下さい
お願いだから
Stop... Stop it, please... I beg of you.
グレッ卜 これは罰だ
Gerd, this is his punishment.
It was wrong of him in the first place to try and monopolize that great knowledge.
あの男が大いなる知識を
独占しようとしたことが
そもそもの間違いなのだ
助けて
Help...
Sylvie, I'm having fun!
シルヴイ ゎしは楽しい
それぞれの経験 それぞれの知識
All kinds of experiences, all kinds of knowledge, all kinds of desires...
それぞれの欲望…
There is no limit to the things one can learn in life!
人生にムダなく
知るベきことに果てはない
ゎしは まだまだ知りたい
I want to learn more and more!
まだまだ食い足り ないのだ シルヴイ
I want to eat more and more, Sylvie!
You ate him, didn't you?!
あの人を… 食ベたのね
あの男の弟として
生まれてきた運命を呪え
Blame your fate for being born as that guy's little brother.
Relax, you will become one inside me.
案ずるな
わしの中でー つにしてやる
You've eaten him?!
食ベたのね )
ぬう
シ シルヴイ…
Sylvie!
マイザ一… 俺は…
Maiza...
I...
捜しましよう セラ一 ドを
Let's look for him, for Szilard!
シ丿しヴィ 貴様 飲まなかったな!?
Sylvie! Bitch, you haven't drunk it, have you?!
ううつ…
ナイ 丿し 貴様~っ
Nile, you bastard!
俺は今 ものすごく
腹を立てているわけだが
I'm pretty damn angry right now,
but let me put this into words instead.
あえて この思いを言葉にしよう
殺す)
I'm gonna kill you!
マイザ一さん
Mr. Maiza...
Sylvie...
シルヴイ 無事か?
You all right?
じやあ 一緒に笑おう
Well then, let's laugh together!
だよな‥
You're right...
じやあ 俺はセラ一ド爺さんを
説得に行くことにするわ
Then, I'll go and try to convince Szilard.
Convince?
説得?
What is there about him that you can convince?
あんな人に
何を説得するというの?
It isn't impossible.
可能性はゼロ じや ない
工ルマ一さん)
Mr. Elmer!
Give up, Mr. Szilard.
観念しろ セラ一ド殿 )
I won't hesitate anymore, Mr. Szilard.
もう迷いはないですよ
セラ一ドさん
Hey, Szilard, you old man!
おお一い! セラ一ドの爺様一つ !
Listen to me!
話を聞いて
ゎつ 痛つ!
Ouch!
工ルマ一 )
Elmer!
マイザアアアア一一ツ
Maiza!
Elmer!
工ルマ一 )
る讀簾の声丿
あの老入の気き夏ノこうとレご
そんなマネき實るとは…
Trying to get the old man's affection, to think you'd try something like that...
お悪変ゎっ庭 ジ…
面白‥… 男渣忍
You sure are strange.
Interesting...
かな
お蔚の願き 7 フ畔え ごやろう
Let me grant you one wish...
As if you were an Arabian Genie.
ノ工ル マ一丿
まる さァ ラとアの簾神左な
C悪簾の声丿
庭左し 願〔 )は3 フさはなく
7 フ左汝喰
However, I will only grant you one wish, not three.
ノ工丿ム マ一丿
よレ 決の宏よ 悪鱒
Okay, I've decided, demon.
Mr. Elmer.
工ルマ一さん)
大丈夫? 工ルマ一さん)
Are you all right, Mr. Elmer?
セラ一 ドの爺様は ?
How is the old man, Szilard?
He fell into the sea. He probably won't come back to the ship, seeing the condition he was in.
海に落ちました あの状態では
船に戻ることはないでしょう
I see...
そうか 説得の余地は
あると思ったんだがな
I thought I'd have a chance at convincing him though.
シルヴイ
Sylvie...
It might be awkward timing, but...
こんな時になんだが
やっぱり笑顔だよ
スマイルだ シ丿しヴィ
put a smile on! Smile, Sylvie!
工ルマ一さん
Mr. Elmer.
私は可能性は
ゼロだと思ってました
I thought you didn't have a chance at all.
そうか…
I see...
俺はまだ
あきらめてないんだけどな
I still haven't given up, though.
グレッ 卜…
Gerd...
C雷簾の声丿
こんなノご早く始まろうとなな
To think it started so fast...
This may sound weird since I'm responsible for these events...
俺が 篇フ庭よ う さなんだか
つくフく入悪とこ )う厘族は欲深‥
Humans really are greedy.
Why are you talking to me?
なぜ私に声をかける
Because you are here.
C悪簾の声丿
そこノごお煎肌 )庭ヵら さ
We're both looking at the situation from a height.
高みの昂 物き蔑め込 乾者周丈
ノ敏長くやろうじゃなC)か
Let's get along.
I'm just interested in what's going on.
私はただ 興味深いだけでね
C悪簾の声丿
御圖悪さ… まぁ ‥‥
We're the same then.
But all right.
今度こ そはと恩 フ庭のだヵ濃
I thought it really would happen this time.
どういう意味だ
What do you mean?
C雷簾の声丿 湯ノご
Nothing in particular, just think of it as a modest idea.
ささやヵな
感慨とフ庭ところだ
まるで我々に何かを
期待しているようだが
It's almost as if you expect us to do something.
る讀簾の声丿
そう せヵすな
Don't rush things.
We're going to be stuck together for a long time to come.
どラせこ力から
長い位き合こ'ノごなるのだヵらな
ま庭胎会う機会もぁるさ
We will meet again.
フ‥ フソ
丿しノラ一夕は
敵に回すと厄介ですが
It will be troublesome to have the Runoratas as our enemy, but...
I think one can safely assume there's no need to fear Gustavo.
グス夕一ヴオという男は 恐れるに
足らずといったところでしょうか
I see.
なるほど では我々は
かかる火の粉を払う以外は
So besides sweeping up the little sparks, there's no need for us to intervene, I take it?
不介入でいいということだな
We shouldn't have any problems then, I think.
問題ないと思ゎれます
マイザ一… 俺はセラ一ドの気配を
すぐそこに感じているのだがな…
Maiza, I can feel that Szilard is right around the corner, though...
お前は何も感じないのか?
Aren't you feeling anything?
まあ いい
But all right.
dokomade mo tsuzuiteru hoshizora miagete utau
I sing, looking up into the endless starry night.
kagiriaru bokutachi no eien wo yume miru melody
A melody in a dream... about our limited eternity.
mune ni afureru itoshisa no mizu wa
This water of love, overflowing from my chest...
mirai no hate de dareka ni todoku darou
I wonder if it will reach someone in the future?
shinjite iruyo
I will believe in you.
harukana toki wo kake nukete
Transcending generations of time...
bokutachi no yobigoe wa itsuka ookina uta ni naru
Will our calls turn into a beautiful song one day?
ai wo tsumuide yukeru yo
You can start building your love,
ima wa mada konnani chiisana hikari dakedo
Though right now, the light is still faint.
Next ep
Preview
Isaac and Miria
Unintentionally Spread Happines Around Them
Miria! They're saying Isaac and Miria sprinkle happiness around without realizing it!
That's amazing, Isaac!
They have the same names as us after all!
The same first and last names!
We have to sprinkle happiness around as well in such a way that we don't lose to this Mr. Isaac and Miss Miria!
I don't really get it, but it's amazing!